{
  "reference_number": "137",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a 2050 target in legislation now",
      "answer_index": 0,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Carbon Dioxide - Reducing net carbon dioxide emissions to zero by 2050",
      "answer_index": 13,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions only (including from new forest planting)",
      "answer_index": 7,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "This is an ambitious and bold target. And it is important for Government to be ambitious and be committed to attempt to reduce\n\n emissions as much as possible."
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "Yes - each incoming Government should have the option to review the third budget in the sequence",
      "answer_index": 14,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "It is important for the Government and Commission to be mindful that change world circumstances financially, technologically,\nscientifically, climatically, socially may impact the target for benefit or for worse."
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Work with the United Nations and the IPCC (Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change) to provide counsel for New Zealand to meet\n\nits targets."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Yes, having a Commission to monitor the Government ensures that goals are being met and are not be avoided. It also allows the\nGovernment to be held accountable as the Commission can say what needs to be done, and if not then there will be consequences."
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": "Advising the Government on policy settings in the NZ ETS",
      "answer_index": 6,
      "notes": "I sit on the fence on the NZ ETS, whilst trading our emissions has been the only option thus far, I think we should not be spending\n\nthe money on credits for other overseas countries to pollute, we should be spending the money on New Zealand emissions\nreduction initiatives."
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Yes, New Zealands contribution to the IPCC (Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change) has one lead author from New Zealand - Dr.\nBronwyn Hayward. There are other experts who should be involved as well such as Dr. Kennedy Graham, Fmr Green Party MP. The\n\nproposed expertise should also include a student representative as they are the future generation that will be living in 2050."
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Carbon emissions and climate change are inter-related."
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Yes, but coastal communities (Dunedin, Westport/Granity) are being impacted as well. We need to think about future planning and\n\nresilience such as should coastal communities relocate, what will happen if insurance providers dont pay out as the home owners\nknew the risk of the location, should we invest in flood mitigation schemes and sea walls etc."
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Yes, ensuring that all stakeholders of the community can contribute and share their thoughts is important."
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "The plan should involve the stopping of importing second hand cars from Japan. Second hand car dealers are still importing cars from\nthe 90's and selling them to New Zealand buyers. If we are to achieve the targets, banning the import and sale of passenger cars to\n\nNew Zealand that are a certain age must be enacted. There should be guidelines that state for example that no car older than\n2005(?) should be imported into New Zealand for sale as a passenger vehicle. In addition to this, providing incentives and tax breaks\nfor car dealerships that make a commitment to import 40% of cars are electric vehicles by 2025 will reduce carbon emissions to\n\nreach the 2050 targets, gradually increasing the 45% to 60% by 2050."
    }
  ]
}
